Anush Raghavender

368-299-0869 | anush.raghavender1@ucalgary.ca | Calgary, Alberta, Canada, T2N5A6

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anush-raghavender | https://anush-raghavender.github.io/profile/

Summary

Skilled software engineer and management graduate with 1.5 years of experience in agile full-stack development. Proficient in solving complex problems and delivering effective technical solutions, with strengths in analytical thinking and communication. Excel in both independent work and team collaboration to achieve business goals.

Education

Haskayne School of Business, University of Calgary | Canada

08/2023 - 08/2024

Master of Management

Indian Institute of Information Technology, Kancheepuram | India

07/2016 - 07/2021

Bachelor & Master of Technology in Computer Science & Engineering

Experience

Student Consultant | Breakwater Vantage | Canada

01/2024 - 03/2024

- Developed UIs for company's new website using React.
- Conducted market research and presented findings and recommendations to the management team.
- Analyzed financial statements, assessed profitability and debt ratios, and performed forecasting.

Software Engineer | Furtim Technologies | India

10/2022 - 07/2023

- Billed 1000+ hours as a technical engineer in the functional consulting department at Leanswift Solutions (a Wipro company), developing UIs for web applications using the InforM3 AngularJS H5 SDK for clients.
- Developed UIs and APIs for an entry management system and a performance analytics system using React and Node for other clients of the company.
- Gathered user requirements, developed logical and physical specifications, and created reports and documentation for my projects.

Business System Analyst | Axis Bank | India

07/2021 - 02/2022

- Developed UIs and APIs for an e-wallet payments application and a document management application using React and Kotlin.
- Automated customer data processing with a Python script, saving 10 manhours weekly.
- Trained in AGILE software development practices.

Others

Skills: Web Development (HTML, CSS, JS, React, Express, Node, MongoDB), Data Analytics (Python, Excel, MySQL, Tableau), Computer Programming (C, C++, Java, Kotlin)

Certifications: Full Stack Development, Data Analytics Essentials

Languages: English, Hindi, Tamil

Hobbies: Chess, Cricket